Glenn Mason

Engineering Manager (Practice Lead) Cloud & DevOps

Glenn J. Mason < glenn@glennji.com> 0434 878088

Sydney, Australia

https://www.linkedin.com/in/glennji/ https://github.com/glennji/ http://glennji.com/

Introduction & Key Skills

I am a passionate engineer (and manager) with more than a decade of commercial experience: developing software, building teams, establishing standards & delivering solutions. I love finding pragmatic and adaptive solutions to the most complex and difficult problems in the world, growing with a team I care about, and seeing our hard work being appreciated by customers "out in the wild".

Cloud: AWS, GCP, Azure, "big data"

DevOps: Kubernetes, Docker, CI/CD, APM, Observability, etc.

Software Dev: Python, Java, Git, Scrum, Reactive, etc.

Experience

Industrie&Co / Engineering Practice Lead (Cloud & DevOps)

FEB 2016 - PRESENT, SYDNEY

Delivering faster, easier, scalable and secure software solutions for start-ups, disruptors and technology companies, while helping make our engineering practice the best in the world.

I&Co is a technology venturing company, forging partnerships with our clients to deliver cutting-edge solutions. Engineering is in my DNA, with a long history of software development, cloud-focused devops and agile practices, and I bring experience and enthusiasm to the difficult problems facing organisations and entrepreneurs today.

As a practice lead, I manage a diverse team of software and DevOps engineers, leading and mentoring as we embrace new technologies and face new problems. I'm also frequently engaged directly with clients in a hands-on development and design role.

ASX / Senior Engineer

ONGOING

We're building a microservice-backed React app for a blockchain-based distributed ledger that will hold over a trillion dollars worth of securities. In just a couple of months, my team and I have designed and built a dynamic GraphQL-based system allowing rapid delivery of new functionality as our underlying systems evolve.

Experience

Atlassian / Consulting Engineer

8 MONTHS

We engaged with Atlassian to assist in the refactor of the core billing system, designing and implementing a Spring Boot microservice for delivery of customer invoices and financial documents, deployed to AWS and integrating with several internal systems.

Compare Asia Group / Consulting Engineer + DevOps

6 MONTHS

I acted as lead for the design and implementation of a Java- and React-based application and microservices for deployment to Istio and Kubernetes.

PwC / Consulting Engineer

4 MONTHS

I worked closely with the PwC development teams to implement several Python microservices for a new AppEngine-based accounting platform.

HIVERY / Consulting Engineer

1 MONTH

I engaged with a Hivery web developer to rapidly develop the Pythonand machine-learning based backend for a React web application, while providing guidance and mentoring to expand his skills. In a month, we took a non-functional prototype and implemented it (MVP), while giving the developer the necessary skills to maintain and extend the Python backend.

Westpac Group / Consulting Engineer

15 MONTHS

As a key part of the Westpac Databank project team, I designed and implemented a cryptographically secure, privacy-protecting data-matching service for use by the DataRepublic Senate platform. This system allows organisations to perform segment analysis of their customers and markets.

Experience

Domain Group / Team Lead, Cloud Platforms

AUG 2018 - FEB 2019, SYDNEY

As the technical team lead, I helped set the direction of the Cloud Platforms team. We provide robust and intelligent platform solutions to empower barrier-free development and innovation for our internal customers at Domain. Whilst with Domain I:

- Implemented the Kubernetes-based platform consisting of several purpose-built clusters running on EC2
- Drove a number of initiatives focused on developer experience, configuration management and "SlackOps" (self-service)
- Established regular reporting and cross-team collaboration
- Mentored and consulted with members of my team regarding best-practices for software development and devops.

RoZetta Technology / Senior Software Engineer

FEB 2015 - FEB 2016, SYDNEY

Applying effective analysis, design, programming and testing skills to produce software systems, while assisting with the technical direction of projects.

As a senior software engineer and lead, I have been responsible for requirements analysis, design and implementation of distributed, cloud-based (Amazon AWS) software systems, mostly in Python. I have also line-managed four technical resources, and provided technical guidance and leadership across the life of a project.

Palantir Technologies / Forward Deployed Engineer

JUL 2012 - NOV 2014, CANBERRA

Be agile, adaptive, technically brilliant -- and deliver.

As a forward-deployed engineer, I was the face of Palantir (demonstrating brilliance and insight, determination to succeed, and commitment to the cause) and its arm and legs (getting things done). I know I've done my job when geeks respect me for my mad skills, management for my approachability and humbleness, and the team for delivering above and beyond expectations.

As such, it was my job to solve "the world's hardest problems":

- Identify, scope and deploy sophisticated deployments
- Develop data integrations, customisations to the Palantir platform and entirely new services using the best possible technology available
- Independently break down and solve complex client problems with little direction

I have built and run a deployment all the way from the initial scoping to hardware installation, system integration, custom code and ongoing maintenance, using a combination of Java, Oracle, Elasticsearch, Cassandra and Gradle.

Experience

Monitise PLC / Software Configuration Manager

AUG 2008 - MAR 2012, LONDON

In an era before "DevOps", my team and I provided that essential function to development teams around the world. I was responsible for:

- Deploying services and applications to test and production
- Publishing packages and libraries for fostering re-use
- Building and supporting the build and support systems
- Proving a cloud-based deployment to Amazon EC2 and RDS

Royal Bank of Scotland / Software Configuration Manager

NOV 2005 - AUG 2008, EDINBURGH

As an agile & motivated member of the large RBS developer community, my responsibilities have included:

- Third-level (technical) production support of Java/Websphere applications
- Implementation of continuous integration (Hudson)
- Proactive system monitoring and the development of patches for improved resilience

GUI Computing / Java Team Lead

JUN 2003 - JUN 2005, MELBOURNE

As the lead developer for a nascent Java team it was my responsibility to design and implement the full Java development environment:

- version control (CVS) and the build system (Apache Ant, Cruise-Control)
- development best-practises including code reviews.

Ordermate / Developer

JUL 2002 - JUN 2003, MELBOURNE

- Development of Java and PHP software
- Administration of Linux file-servers and application platform.
- Test-process design (including test cases and field testing).

Pracom / Developer

MAR 2000 - APR 2002, MELBOURNE

- Design and develop new telephony products using core architecture guidelines
- Design and develop the core offline billing engine
- Providing ongoing reports to the Project Management department

Education

Swinburne University of Technology / B. Sci (applied)

GRADUATED 2005

A diverse undergraduate course covering topics including software engineering, hardware, operating systems and networking. Included CCNA and MCSE accredited training.

Swinburne University of Technology / MBA

IN PROGRESS

Offered though Swinburne Online, the Masters of Business Administration course is providing a wider context around business, entrepreneurship, organisational challenges and finance.